我想出了一个科学笑话 你想听吗?
I've invented a science joke, would you like to hear it?
当然
Sure.
扭进一个灯泡需要多少个爱迪生?
How many Edisons does it take to screw in a light bulb?
多少个?
How many?
无所谓 灯泡的主意是他剽窃的
Who cares? He stole the idea
所以他没资格有自己的笑话
and doesn't deserve his own joke.
真的是剽窃的吗?
Is that really true?
当然 这才算是好笑话
Of course, that's how you know it's a good joke.
不仅有娱乐性 还能教人知识
It not only entertains, it informs.
嘿 抱歉打扰了
Hey, sorry to interrupt.
呃 Barry
Uh, Barry,
扭进一个灯泡需要多少个爱迪生?
uh, how many Edisons does it take to screw in a light bulb?
你知道其实爱迪生没有发明灯泡吧?
Did you know Edison didn't actually invent the light bulb?
你来干嘛 Barry?
What do you want, Barry?
只是想把这份小谢礼送给Amy
Just wanted to drop this off as a little thank you for Amy.
谢我什么?
What's this for?
你的主意真的帮了大忙
Your idea really helped me out.
我的光锥量子化论文已经上线了
My light-cone quantization paper's online already.
反响非常热烈
The response has been amazing.
真是太好了
Well, that's fascinating.
我等不及拜读了
I can't wait to read it.
哦 我也是
Oh, no, me as well.
请发送到Sheldon@逗你玩 点 鄙之
Uh, please e-mail it to Sheldon@Bazinga.biz.
为什么用"点 鄙之"?
Why "dot-biz"?
因为我刚鄙视你了
Because I just gave you the business.
(.com其实是常用域名后缀 为和前面笑点统一 此处没有直译)
而且 逗你玩 点 康姆 被人注册掉了
And also Bazinga.com was taken.
再次感谢你
Anyway, thanks again.
Cooper 滚蛋去
Cooper, suck eggs.
你什么时候开始帮Barry Kripke了?
Since when do you help out Barry Kripke?
我一直试图从细胞自动机的角度研究
Well, I'd been thinking about a cellular automata approach
神经元连通性
to neuronal connectivity,
我觉得它在弦理论领域可能会有一些
and I thought it might have some interesting applications
有趣的应用... 没什么大不了的
to string theory... it's not a big deal.
真的吗?
Oh, really?
当我研究弦理论碰壁的时候
When I was doing string theory and hit a dead end,
你为什么没试着帮我?
why didn't you try to help me?
我想帮你的... 但你说生物学家唯一会做的算数
I did ... you said the only math biologists know is
就是如果你有三只青蛙 一只跳走了
if you have three frogs and one hops away,
那就只剩两只青蛙了
that leaves two frogs.
真有趣 听着的确像我说的
That's pretty funny, that does sound like me.
但这并不意味着
But that doesn't mean
你就应该站在街角
that you should be standing on street corners
把你的数学理论送给路过的陌生人
handing out your math to whatever guy comes along.
Sheldon 我们都是科学家
Sheldon, we're all scientists.
我帮了一个同事
I helped out a fellow colleague.
你太小气了
You're being petty.
我小气?
I'm being petty?
你明知道我和Barry在研究上是竞争关系
You know Barry and I have a professional rivalry.
你也听到他说的了... 他让我滚蛋
You heard him... he told me to suck eggs.
如果我们是朋友 他就会让我去
If we were friends, he would have suggested
滚点好东西
I suck something more pleasant.
你干嘛笑?
Why are you laughing?
你学到什么了吗?
Did you learn something?
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季第15集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥的意思是学酥
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理
翻译: 酱油影 凤梨酥 奥利奥 上等五仁儿
好的 妈妈
Okay, Ma.
替我跟Gladys姑姑问好
Say hi to Aunt Gladys.
好 我也爱你
Yeah, I love you, too.
再见
Bye.
你妈妈在弗洛里达玩得开心吗?
Your mom having fun in Florida?
她很喜欢那里
Mmm, she loves it.
她终于找到个所有人都在说自己
She finally found a place where everyone talks about
满身臭汗的地方了
how sweaty they are.
还有 她让我们去她家一次
Anyway, she wants us to go to the house
看看Stuart怎么样 因为他可能会"寂寞"
and check in on Stuart because he might be "lonely."
她只是很友善而已
She's just being nice.
我是她儿子 她怎么就不派个人过来
Well, I'm her son, how come she doesn't send someone
看看我有没有寂寞呢?
to check on me if I'm lonely?
因为你有老婆
Because you have a wife.
没错 但你有时候会加班
Yeah, well, sometimes you work late.
我知道你不喜欢Stuart住在你妈家里
I know you don't like Stuart being in the house,
但漫画店马上就要重新开张了
but the store's about to reopen,
我想他会很快东山再起的
I'm sure he'll get back on his feet.
那就好了
That would be great.
我也希望我和我妈妈之间的关系能恢复正常
I'd love for things between me and Mom to get back to normal.
"正常"言过其实了 不过也行
Well, normal's a strong word, but sure.
- 你好  - 不好
- Hey.  - Hello.
你没事吧?
You okay?
如果我没事 我就会说"你好"了
If I was okay, I would've said "hello"
而不是死气沉沉的"不好"
and not the much more ominous "hello."
出什么事了?
What's going on?
我在生Amy的气
I'm mad at Amy.
她也在你最喜欢的露脐装上留了油渍?
Did she leave pit stains in your favorite crop top, too?
没有
No.
她帮Barry Kripke在弦理论领域实现了突破
She helped Barry Kripke make an advancement in string theory.
听起来是件好事呀
Oh, that sounds like a good thing.
本来是好事 但我就是因为以为
Well, it would be, except that I left string theory
弦理论没戏了才放弃的
because I decided it was a dead end.
没错 然后她就背着我
Yeah, and then she went behind my back
帮别人证明我是错的
to help someone else prove me wrong.
偏偏帮的还是我的对手
My rival, no less.
抱歉让你看到我这样子
I'm sorry you had to see that.
抱歉我竟然没带相机
I'm sorry I didn't have a camera.
她为什么要这么对我?
Why would she do this to me?
我想她应该不是故意气你的
Well, I'm sure she didn't upset you on purpose.
而且 你不是经常说
Besides, aren't you the one who says
"没有比科学进步更重要了的"吗?
there's nothing more important than the advancement of science?
不 我说的是"没有比我让科学进步
No, I said there's nothing more important
更重要了的"
than me advancing science.
好吧 如果我没理解错的话
All right, well, if I'm understanding this right,
她只不过是帮了另外一个科学家
and all she did was help out another scientist,
我想这件事你应该随它去吧
I'm thinking you might have to let this one go.
"随它吧"
Ugh, "let it go."
我听了一辈子这句话
I have heard that my whole life.
每次我郁闷的时候 就会有人跟我说 "别想它了"
Every time something upsets me somebody says, "let it go,"
就好像是我的错似的
you know, like it's my fault,
而且我难过也不行
and it's not okay to feel the way I feel.
我也不知道怎么劝你
I don't know what to tell you.
你和她谈谈啊
I mean, why don't you talk to her?
你就这点本事吗?
Is that all you have?
老生常谈的"和她谈谈"还有“别想它了”?
Shopworn tidbits like "talk to her" and "let it go"?
天啊 Penny 生活就这么欺骗了我
Gee, Penny, life's giving me lemons.
我还能怎么办?
What should I do?
你可以把他推倒在一边
Well, you could shove them somewhere.
不错 这样就有趣多了
Okay, now you're getting creative.
太谢谢你们来帮忙了
Thanks again for your help.
- 没事  - 不用客气
- No problem.  - Our pleasure.
这里看起来真棒
The place really looks great.
是啊 你早几年就应该一把火烧了以前的店面
Yeah, you should have burned it down years ago.
我说过多少次了 我没放火
I keep telling you I didn't burn it down.
我们懂的 懂的... 因为放火烧房子
We know, we know ... because burning something down
骗保险赔款是"违法"的
for the insurance money is a "crime."
Stuart 这里好漂亮
Stuart, this place looks amazing.
谢了
Thanks.
你做的真不错
You really did a nice job.
谢谢你这段时间一直
And thank you for putting up with me
同意我住在你妈妈那里
staying at your mom's through all this.
如果不是这样 我肯定没法重新开业
I... I couldn't have done it otherwise.
不用客气 我也很开心看到...
I appreciate that, and I'm glad you were able to...
那是我妈妈的家具吗?
Is that my mother's furniture?
是啊 她说我可以搬过来用
Yeah, she said I could use it.
看起来多好!
Doesn't it look great?
我觉得不如以前在客厅里的样子好
Not as great as it looks in the den where it belongs.
淡定 Howie
Howie.
你怎么不干脆吧整个房子都洗劫一空?
Why don't you just clean out the whole room?
把我三年级给她做的绳编小丑
Take the string art clown I made her in third grade
和我游泳课上因为能把脸放进水里
and the ribbon I got in swim class
而赢得的缎带都拿走
for putting my face in the water.
你没事吧?
What is your problem?
她都说我可以搬走家具了
She said it was okay.
我是他的儿子 我觉得不可以
Well, I'm her son, and I say it's not okay.
儿子... 看起来你做那个小丑也就花了十分钟
Some son ... looks like you spent ten minutes on that clown art.
是不是我也应该像你一样 去读个艺术学校
Well, maybe I should've gone to a fancy art school like you.
这样我就可以开一间倒闭的漫画书店
Then I could run a failed comic shop
然后勾搭别人的妈妈了
and mooch off some guy's mother.
我们先走吧 你冷静一下
Why don't we leave so you can cool off?
有道理
I think that's a good idea.
让他滚出我的店
Take him out of my store.
你的店?!
Your store?!
是我妈妈给你钱让你重新开业的
My mother gave you the money to reopen.
我还就不走了
I'm not going anywhere.
咱们去买点聚会要吃的东西吧
Why don't we go get the food for the party.
谢了
Thank you.
机智... 看起来咱们帮了大忙了
Smart ... looks like we're being helpful.
是啊 其实咱们是逃离了
Mmm, when really we're just exiting
一个尴尬的场合
an uncomfortable situation.
Kripke 你知道么 所有人里... Barry Kripke他
Kripke, you know, of all the people ... Barry Kripke.
我真是... 你这样像疯子一样叠衣服
I'm so... Are you folding it like a crazy person
是想让我帮你叠吗?!
to get me to do it for you?!
不是
No.
天啊 我来吧
Oh, give me that.
我很好奇
Just out of curiosity,
如果我想放下一件事
if I were to let something go,
应该怎么做呢?
how would I do that?
我也不知道... 就试着想想别的事吧
I don't know... just think about something else.
我可以想针鼹嘛?
Can I think about the spiny anteater?
当然
Sure.
针鼹...
The spiny anteater...
从来不会背叛我而去帮Barry Kripke
never went behind my back and worked with Barry Kripke.
一点用都没有
That didn't help at all.
你知道吗 有的时候人们会用视觉化的方式
You know, some people try visualization.
那要怎么做?
How does that work?
这样
Okay,
把你纠结的问题想象成一支笔
imagine your problems are a pen.
好的
Okay.
现在想象你自己正拿着那支笔
Now imagine you're holding that pen.
好
Okay.
现在张开手掌 放开那支笔
Now open your hand and let it go.
可是我才刚拿到啊
But I just got this pen.
上面刻了我名字的首字母什么的呢
It's got my initials on it and everything.
听着
Look.
Sheldon 没那么难的
Sheldon, this isn't that hard.
没准按我说的做你才能帮到我
I may have a better way that you can teach me.
怎么做?
How?
如果我告诉你 在过去的几个月里
What if I told you that over the past few months
Any一直偷偷在用你做实验
Amy has secretly been giving you little puzzles
对比你的智商和她实验室里大猩猩的智商 你会怎么想?
to test your intelligence against chimpanzees in her lab?
什么? 她才没有用我做实验
What? She didn't give me any puzzles.
你确定?
Are you sure?
天啊 我拼不起来这把剪刀了
Boy, I just can't seem to get these scissors back together.
你能弄好吗?
Can you do it?
该死
Darn it.
我眼睛里进了东西
There's something in my eye,
我得按大小把这些硬币分类
and I need to sort these coins by size.
能帮个忙吗?
Can you help?
嘿 Penny?
Penny?
我想吃这个香蕉
I really want to eat this banana,
可是它卡在这个迷宫盒子里了
but it's stuck inside this bamboo puzzle box.
我勒个去!
Son of a bitch!
这样就对了
Okay, that's great.
现在 别去想它了
Now, let it go.
真不敢相信你们居然对比我和大猩猩的智商!
I can't believe you were testing me against a chimp!
跟我没关系 是Amy在测试
Well, excuse me, Amy was testing you.
我是支持你的
I was rooting for you.
对了 香蕉那个你做的真不错
Good job on that banana box, by the way.
她为什么要这么做?
Why would she even do this?
她在用大猩猩做一系列实验
She's been conducting an experiment on apes
让大猩猩们解决各种难题
where they're given various puzzles to solve.
我很惊讶于这些问题的复杂程度
I was surprised at the complexity of the puzzles
并且认为 有些问题是人类都很难解决的
and thought some humans wouldn't be able to solve them.
后来Amy说 "想不想让实验变得更有趣?"
That's when Amy said, "Want to make this interesting?"
"更有趣?"
"Make this interesting"?
你们拿我打赌?
You bet money on me?
不是 不是
No, no.
我们设计了个涉及你的实验
We designed an experiment involving you.
看见没? 是不是很有趣?
See? Now, isn't that interesting?
这哪里有趣
It's not interesting.
根本就是羞辱人
It's incredibly insulting.
好吧 或许这会有帮助...
Okay, maybe this will help ...
想象你正拿着一支笔
imagine you're holding a pen.
别想太远 这笔很普通
Before you go too far, not a special pen
上面没有刻着你的名字...
with your initials engraved on it ...
不然接下去就很难放手了
that'll make the next part really hard.
哦...
Oh...
够了
That's it.
出去!
Get out!
我不明白你为什么对我生气
I don't understand why you're mad at me.
你该生气的是Amy
You should be mad at Amy.
就跟我今天下午那样
Like I was this afternoon.
嘿 你瞧瞧... 我放下这事了
Hey, look at that ... I let it go.
出去!
Get out!
- Penny?  - 怎么了?
- Penny?  - What?
我好像把笔落里面了
I think I left my pen in there.
我明白你为什么生气
I understand why you're upset,
但他费了很大的劲才整顿好店面的
but he worked really hard to get the store ready.
而且这不过是套家具
And it's just furniture.
这是我妈的家具
It's my mom's furniture.
它应该待在我长大的房子里...
It belongs in the house I grew up in...
旁边靠着一堆"电视指南"
next to that pile of TV Guides
放眼看去 对一个十岁小孩来说 就是
and in plain view of what, for a ten-year-old, was
一幅高质量的编图艺术!
a quality piece of string art!
Howie 要是店开成了 Stuart有了收入来源
Howie, if the store succeeds, Stuart has a source of income,
就能搬出你妈的房子了
and he can move out of your mother's house.
看起来用套旧家具换这一切
Seems like some old furniture is a reasonable price
也挺划算的
to pay for that.
这是个好点子
That is a good point.
但我娶你不是为了好点子
But I didn't marry you for good points.
我娶你为的是盲目地支持我
I married you to blindly support me
不管我有多么荒谬!
no matter how ridiculous I'm being!
这就是为什么我要重写我们的结婚誓言
This is why I had to rewrite our wedding vows.
嗨 我们是来取漫画中心的订餐的
Hi, we're here to pick up an order for Comic Center.
好得 让我先查查
Sure, let me go check on that.
老兄 我... 我觉得那人是Nathan Fillion
Dude, I... I think that's Nathan Fillion.
是啊 还真是
Oh yeah, look at that.
他还把沙拉里的番茄挑出来了
And he's picking the tomatoes out of his salad
就跟我一样
just like I do.
我一直觉得跟他心灵相通
I always did feel a connection with him.
我有个主意了
Oh, I have got an idea.
我们不拿他的番茄放eBay上卖
We're not selling his tomatoes on eBay.
不 如果我们请到电影"萤火虫"里的雷诺上尉
No, if we got Captain Reynolds from Firefly
去Stuart的店里签售
to do a signing at Stuart's store,
那就酷毙了
that would be amazing.
的确很酷
That would be great.
那我们去跟他谈谈?
So should we go talk to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说 如果他人不友善 我日后就看不下
I mean, if he's not nice, it's gonna make it hard for me
- 任何他演的剧了  - 什么?!
- to watch him in anything again.  - What?!
那个... 那个演琼·斯诺的人是个混蛋
The... the guy who plays Jon Snow was a jerk.
我们不照样看"权力的游戏"
We still watch Game of Thrones.
他是个混蛋因为你跟他撞尾了
He was a jerk because you rear-ended him.
我分心了
I was distracted.
看到守夜人的一员开着绑着皮船的车
It's weird seeing a member of the Night's Watch
很奇怪的
with a kayak strapped to his car.
去吧
Come on.
嗨 打扰一下 先... 先...
Hi, excuse me, s... s...
我... 我不是有意打扰你
I... I don't mean to bother you,
但我们是电影"萤火虫"的铁粉
but we're just really big fans of Firefly.
还... 还有"恐怖博士"
A... and Dr. Horrible.
哦 我觉得你们找错人了
Oh, uh, I think you made a mistake.
我不是演员
I'm not an actor.
别这么说
Don't say that.
我的意思是 你虽然不是Dame Judi Dench
I mean, you're not Dame Judi Dench,
但也挺厉害的
but you're pretty great.
哦 这下我明白了... 你们是把我认成内森·菲利安了
Oh, yeah, I get it ... you think I'm Nathan Fillion,
但我不是
but I'm not.
所以若不介意的话 我想把我的午饭吃完
So if you don't mind, I would just love to eat my lunch.
走吧
Come on.
不好意思打扰了
Sorry to bother you.
不知道为什么他脾气这么差
Don't know why he's so grumpy.
我有次被认成了"少年派"里的主角
I got mistaken for that guy in Life of Pi once,
现在还沾沾自喜呢
and I'm still floating.
Sheldon 是我
Sheldon, it's me.
哦 嘿
Oh, hey.
你... 你刚刚看见了吗?
D... did you see that?
我... 我知道怎么自己开门了
I... I figured out how to open the door all by myself.
我或许该丢几把笼子边的粑粑庆祝下
Maybe I'll fling some feces around my cage to celebrate.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我知道了你一直在暗中给我解谜测试
I know you've been giving me secret puzzle tests.
SHeldon 开门
Sheldon, open the door.
不行
I can't.
我光着身子呢
I'm naked.
我刚刚看见你了
I just saw you.
等等
Hang on.
马上开门
Open the door now.
- 哦 嘿  - 把裤子拉好
- Oh, hey.  - Pull up your pants!
没什么大不了的
It's not a big deal.
我一直在大学生上做这样的测试
I run tests like this on undergrads all the time.
如果你去大学里填个表
If you fill out some paperwork at the university,
我可以给你五块钱
I can get you $5.
我不要五块钱
I don't want $5.
我要的是尊严
I want my dignity.
那你说怎么样 十块钱?
So what are we talking, like, ten bucks?
- 谢谢你  - 谢谢
- Thank you.  - Thanks.
- 再次抱歉  - 没事
- Sorry again.  - No problem.
你... 你确定不是他吗?
A... are you sure you're not him?
呃 你可以放心得说
Uh, you can tell us.
我们是科学家 不是狂热的粉丝
We're scientists, not crazy fanboys.
那好吧
All right, fine.
我就是他
I'm him.
而你在熟食店独自用餐
And you're eating alone at a deli.
我才不信... 你不是他本人
I don't buy it ... you're not him.
我就是想安静地吃顿午饭
I just wanted to eat my lunch in peace.
但我真是本人
But I really am him.
还有谢谢你们这些粉丝
And thank you very much for being a fan.
愿意的话 我们可以合个影
If you want, uh, let's take a picture.
那太好了
That would be great.
太好了 谢谢
Great. Yeah, thank you.
来吧
You bet.
等等
Wait, hang on.
如果你真是Nathan Fillion
If you're really Nathan Fillion,
那么你在Firefly里 帽子那句台词是什么?
what's the line from Firefly about your bonnet?
"以我美丽的花般的软帽起誓 我将会终结你"
"I swear by my pretty floral bonnet, I will end you."
完全正确 就是这句
That's it, that's the line.
尽管如此...
Although...
我也知道这句台词... 但这并不代表我就是Nathan Fillion
I knew the line ... doesn't make me Nathan Fillion.
到底还想不想要合影了?
Do you want the picture or not?
我只想和真的Nathan Fillion合影
I want a picture with Nathan Fillion.
那么跟一个烦躁版的Nathan Fillion
How about a picture with a guy who looks like Nathan Fillion
合一张影怎么样呢?
but a little more annoyed than Nathan Fillion usually is?
怎么样?
What do you think?
发Facebook倒是够了
Eh, it's good enough for Facebook.
真不敢相信他们能做出这种事
I can't believe they did that.
是啊... 简直是侮辱
I know ... it's so insulting.
有一回 他们让我想办法
At one point, they had me figure out
把一根香蕉从一个盒子里取出来
how to get a banana out of a puzzle box.
等等 Sheldon给过我一个藏着香蕉的盒子
Wait, Sheldon gave me a banana in a box.
他也给我做了测试
He was testing me, too.
不可理喻
Unbelievable.
黑猩猩怎么能够取出香蕉?
And how could a chimp even solve that?
那也太难了
That was impossible.
真的吗? 你没拿出来?
Really? You couldn't get it out?
谢谢
Thank you.
这店太棒了
Wow, the store looks great.
你们俩在测试我们吗?
So you guys were testing us both?
你们到底怎么回事?
What is the matter with you?
他们俩就是
Eh, what's the matter with them is
自以为聪明过人
they think they're so smart they don't care
根本不考虑是否伤害了别人
if they hurt other people's feelings.
- 好像是  - 不是这样的
- Sounds like us.  - That's not true.
我还是不明白你为什么生气
I still don't understand why you're upset.
所有题目你都比猩猩解得快
You solved every puzzle faster than all of the chimps.
除了Barnabas 但是他服用了Adderall
Well, except Barnabas, but he was on Adderall.
一种治疗注意力缺失 多动症的药物
对不起 但真的让我抓狂啊
I'm sorry, but it's making me crazy.
能不能别再想了?
Can you please just let it go?
我能帮你
Oh, I can help you with that.
想象你拿着一根很普通的笔
Imagine you're holding an ordinary pen.
而你最爱的那根 很安全地躺在你的口袋里
While your favorite pen is safe and secure in your pocket.
保持住
Hold that thought.
你好?
Hello?
我怎样才能弥补你?
How can I make this up to you?
答案藏在这里
The answer's in this puzzle box.
看看你能不能打开
Let's see if you can open it.
你至少可以告诉他家具的事
You could have at least warned him about the furniture.
搬的时候我就这么说过
That's what I said when we moved it.
你帮他搬的?!
You helped him?!
没有 Stuart自己选的那些抱枕
No, Stuart picked out those throw pillows all on his own.
你还好吧?
Hey, you okay?
不好
Uh, no.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
嗯...
Um...
我妈妈去世了
my mom died.
什么?
What?
呃...
Uh...
我姑姑打来的
that was my aunt.
妈小睡了一下
Ma took a nap.
就再没醒来
She never woke up.
哦我的上帝 Howie
Oh, my God, Howie.
节哀顺变
I'm so sorry.
我们能做点什么?
What can we do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我能说句话吗?
May I say something?
现在别 Sheldon
Not right now, Sheldon.
但应该能安慰他
But I think it would be comforting.
- 哥们...  - 没事 说吧
- Buddy...  - No, it's okay.
什么?
What?
我爸爸去世的时候
When I lost my own father,
没有任何朋友陪伴我
I didn't have any friends to help me through it.
但是你有
You do.
我真以为他会说 "随它去吧"
I really thought he was gonna say, "Let it go."
好的 谢谢 Bernadette
Okay, thanks, Bernadette.
一路平安
Travel safe.
好 拜拜
Okay, bye.
他们订了机票
They booked a flight.
在去机场的路上
They're heading to the airport now.
Howard怎么样?
How's Howard holding up?
还挺得住
He's hanging in there.
你没事吧 Stuart?
How are you doing, Stuart?
还是不敢相信她走了
Still can't believe she's gone.
是她收留了我
I mean, that woman took me in.
要不是她 我... 我还流落街头呢
If it wasn't for her, I... I would have been homeless.
我们中总会有人收留你的
One of us would have taken you in.
是嘛 我怎么没印象有人邀请过我
Yeah, I don't recall any offers.
但是 我... 我很欣慰是现在这个结果
But, you know, uh, I... I'm glad it worked out the way it did
因为我能认识这个好人
because I got to know this wonderful person.
是啊
Yeah.
Wolowitz女士真的很与众不同
Mrs. Wolowitz was pretty special.
我刚来美国时
When I first moved to America,
Howard是我唯一的朋友
Howard was my only friend.
她非常热情好客
She made me feel so welcome in her home.
因为那几年
Which says a lot, because, those first few years,
她以为我是花匠
she thought I was the gardener.
每次我见到她
Whenever I saw her,
她都说我太瘦了 要喂我东西吃
she'd say I was too skinny and try and feed me.
她也喂我东西吃
She did that to me, too.
别跟我抢
Don't take this away from me.
我不烦她的呐喊
I didn't care for her yelling.
但是我再也听不到了
But now that I'm not going to hear it again,
我好难过
I'm sad.
我一会儿可以冲你喊
If you want, I can yell at you later.
你喊不出那感觉
It won't be as good.
我们干个杯吧
Let's have a toast.
敬Wolowitz女士
To Mrs. Wolowitz.
我们共同的...
A loving mother...
亲爱的妈妈
to all of us.
我们会想念你的
We'll miss you.